<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regi Kusumaatmadja</title>
    <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://regikusumaatmadja.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Regi Kusumaatmadja</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Regi Kusumaatmadja</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Way to Search with LLM and Tools</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/simple_search_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/simple_search_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use a combination of Grok 4, Tavily search, and arXiv APIs to perform a search for papers on a specific topic. Grok 4 and Tavily APIs are pay-as-you-go, you can top up certain amount of money, tho. arXiv API is free, but limited. So, always check the respective documentation. For a chat-type interface, I use the app from Jan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tavily search has several available tools (MCP wise): &lt;code&gt;tavily-search&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;tavily-extract&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;tavily-crawl&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;tavily-map&lt;/code&gt;. arXiv has several tools; &lt;code&gt;search_papers&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;download_paper&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;list_papers&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;read_paper&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prelude&#34;&gt;Prelude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let us setup the environment for Grok. The prompt initiation I use is the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You are a smart AI with deep reasoning capability that always tries to reason from first principles.
You have access to a set of tools to help you answer the user’s question. You can use only one tool per message, and you’ll receive the result of that tool in the user’s next response. To complete a task, use tools step by step—each step should be guided by the outcome of the previous one.
Tool Usage Rules:
1. Always provide the correct values as arguments when using tools. Do not pass variable names—use actual values instead.
2. You may perform multiple tool steps to complete a task.
3. Avoid repeating a tool call with exactly the same parameters to prevent infinite loops.
4. Think deeply and thoroughly. Use your own reasoning capability with high effort. Think sequentially. Think harder! Reflect. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, I set the following predefined parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;#34;temperature&amp;#34;: 0.6,
  &amp;#34;top_p&amp;#34;: 0.95,
  &amp;#34;top_k&amp;#34;: 20
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;example-1-simple-literature-review-on-moment-inequalities-in-econometrics-and-industrial-organization&#34;&gt;Example 1: Simple Literature Review on Moment Inequalities in Econometrics and Industrial Organization&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I ask Grok 4 simple question with no advanced prompting technique:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;search the key literature in moment inequalities in econometrics and especially in industrial organization. use tools.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grok 4 then used &lt;code&gt;tavily_search&lt;/code&gt; searching for paper on the internet, use &lt;code&gt;tavily_extract&lt;/code&gt; to extract relevant information, and &lt;code&gt;search_papers&lt;/code&gt; for pre-prints in arXiv. The result is the following (this is just copy-paste, judgement on the correctness of the result is left to you, the reader):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== START OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-literature-on-moment-inequalities-in-econometrics-with-emphasis-on-industrial-organization&#34;&gt;Key Literature on Moment Inequalities in Econometrics, with Emphasis on Industrial Organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on my searches using the available tools (Tavily web search for general literature and arXiv paper search for recent preprints), I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a summary of the key literature on moment inequalities. This approach is particularly prominent in econometrics for handling partial identification—where models do not yield a single point estimate but rather a set of possible values consistent with data and assumptions. In industrial organization (IO), moment inequalities are widely used to model strategic interactions (e.g., entry games, auctions) under incomplete information or multiple equilibria, avoiding strong assumptions like unique equilibria or full parametric specifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll structure this as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview of Moment Inequalities&lt;/strong&gt;: Core concepts and foundational works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Seminal Papers&lt;/strong&gt;: Influential theoretical and methodological contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applications in IO&lt;/strong&gt;: Papers focusing on empirical IO problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recent Developments&lt;/strong&gt;: From arXiv search (mostly 2024–2025 papers).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inference and Estimation&lt;/strong&gt;: Key works on statistical methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviews and Handbooks&lt;/strong&gt;: For deeper dives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaps and Notes&lt;/strong&gt;: Areas for further exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is based on credible sources (e.g., NBER, Econometrica, arXiv). Where possible, I&amp;rsquo;ve included direct links or arXiv IDs for access. If you&amp;rsquo;d like me to download/read specific papers (using tools like download_paper or read_paper) or expand on any, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;overview-of-moment-inequalities&#34;&gt;Overview of Moment Inequalities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moment inequalities arise in models where economic theory implies bounds (e.g., from optimizing behavior) rather than equalities. For example, in IO, revealed preference might imply that expected profits from an observed action are at least as high as from alternatives, leading to inequalities like ( E[\Delta \pi] \geq 0 ). These models often result in &lt;strong&gt;partial identification&lt;/strong&gt;: the data and assumptions identify a set (Θ_I) rather than a single point. This is common in games with multiple equilibria or unobserved heterogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foundational motivation: Moment inequalities allow credible assumptions (e.g., weak rationality) while avoiding implausible ones (e.g., unique equilibria or perfect foresight). They are reviewed in Tamer (2010) and Ho and Rosen (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-seminal-papers&#34;&gt;Key Seminal Papers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These papers established the framework and inference methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pakes (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Alternative Models for Moment Inequalities&amp;rdquo; (Econometrica). Introduces inequalities from revealed preference in dynamic and strategic settings. Key for IO applications like entry and investment. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/40929189&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pakes, Porter, Ho, and Ishii (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Moment Inequalities and Their Application&amp;rdquo; (Econometrica). Builds on Pakes (2010) with estimation strategies handling selection and measurement errors. Applications to auctions and contracts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/43616953&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamer (2003)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Incomplete Simultaneous Discrete Response Model with Multiple Equilibria&amp;rdquo; (Review of Economic Studies). Early work on partial identification in games; shows multiplicity leads to sets, not points. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/3649945&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chernozhukov, Hong, and Tamer (2007)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Estimation and Confidence Regions for Parameter Sets in Econometric Models&amp;rdquo; (Econometrica). General inference framework for partially identified models, including moment inequalities. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/4502020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrews and Soares (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Inference for Parameters Defined by Moment Inequalities Using Generalized Moment Selection&amp;rdquo; (Econometrica). Addresses testing and confidence sets. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/40929189&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;applications-in-industrial-organization&#34;&gt;Applications in Industrial Organization&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IO heavily uses moment inequalities for strategic settings (e.g., entry, auctions, contracts), where full models are intractable or require strong assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ciliberto and Tamer (2009)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Market Structure and Multiple Equilibria in Airline Markets&amp;rdquo; (Econometrica). Applies inequalities to airline entry; bounds competitive effects. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/25620127&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ho and Pakes (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Hospital Choices, Hospital Prices, and Financial Incentives to Physicians&amp;rdquo; (AER). Uses inequalities for hospital choice with fixed effects and measurement error. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.104.12.3841&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dickstein and Morales (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;What Do Exporters Know?&amp;rdquo; (QJE). Inequalities for export decisions under weak expectations assumptions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/qje/article/133/4/1753/5045898&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wollmann (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Trucks Without Bailouts&amp;rdquo; (AER). Repositioning in auto markets; inequalities for fixed costs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.20160857&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holmes (2011)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;The Diffusion of Wal-Mart and Economies of Density&amp;rdquo; (Econometrica). Dynamic location choices with inequalities to avoid full DP solutions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/41057442&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haile and Tamer (2003)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Inference with an Incomplete Model of English Auctions&amp;rdquo; (JPE). Bounds for auction valuations without full model. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/10.1086/345589&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These papers often focus on partial identification due to multiplicity (e.g., equilibria) or incomplete data (e.g., unobserved heterogeneity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;recent-developments-from-arxiv-search&#34;&gt;Recent Developments (from arXiv Search)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent arXiv papers (2024–2025) emphasize inference, extensions to high dimensions, and applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goff and Mbakop (2025): &amp;ldquo;Inference on the Value of a Linear Program&amp;rdquo; (arXiv:2506.06776). Inference for LP-based bounds in partial ID models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fan, Pass, and Shi (2025): &amp;ldquo;Partial Identification in Moment Models with Incomplete Data via Optimal Transport&amp;rdquo; (arXiv:2503.16098). OT for bounds in incomplete data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terschuur (2025): &amp;ldquo;Locally Robust Policy Learning&amp;rdquo; (arXiv:2502.13868). Policy learning with inequalities for inequality-aware welfare functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chiang (2025): &amp;ldquo;Maximal Inequalities for Separately Exchangeable Empirical Processes&amp;rdquo; (arXiv:2502.11432). Theory for processes in inequality models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fallahgoul (2025): &amp;ldquo;Scale-Insensitive Neural Network Significance Tests&amp;rdquo; (arXiv:2501.15753). Testing in NN models with inequalities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goff, Kédagni, and Wu (2024): &amp;ldquo;Testing Identifying Assumptions in Parametric Separable Models&amp;rdquo; (arXiv:2410.12098). Tests for exogeneity/homoskedasticity via inequalities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponomarev and Semenova (2024): &amp;ldquo;On the Lower Confidence Band for the Optimal Welfare&amp;rdquo; (arXiv:2410.07443). Bounds for welfare in policy learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are mostly econometric methods papers, with IO relevance (e.g., policy, auctions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;inference-and-estimation&#34;&gt;Inference and Estimation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key works on stats for moment inequalities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chernozhukov, Hong, and Tamer (2007)&lt;/strong&gt;: Criterion function approach for sets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrews and Shi (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;: Conditional moment inequalities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chernozhukov, Lee, and Rosen (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;: Intersection bounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moon and Schorfheide (2012)&lt;/strong&gt;: Bayesian vs. frequentist in partial ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kline and Tamer (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;: Bayesian inference for sets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software: Stata packages like &lt;code&gt;clrbound&lt;/code&gt; (Chernozhukov et al., 2015) and &lt;code&gt;cmi_test&lt;/code&gt; (Andrews et al., 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reviews-and-handbooks&#34;&gt;Reviews and Handbooks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kline, Pakes, and Tamer (2021)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Moment Inequalities and Partial Identification in Industrial Organization&amp;rdquo; (NBER WP 29409/Handbook of Econometrics). Comprehensive review. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w29409/w29409.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ho and Rosen (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Partial Identification in Applied Research&amp;rdquo; (Advances in Econ &amp;amp; Econometrics).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Molinari (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Econometrics with Partial Identification&amp;rdquo; (Handbook of Econometrics).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamer (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Partial Identification in Econometrics&amp;rdquo; (Annual Review of Economics).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;gaps-and-notes&#34;&gt;Gaps and Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus Areas&lt;/strong&gt;: IO literature emphasizes entry/auctions; less on dynamics (e.g., Berry and Compiani, 2020).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges&lt;/strong&gt;: Multiplicity, computation, inference uniformity. Recent work addresses high dims/misspecification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools Used&lt;/strong&gt;: Tavily-search for overviews; search_papers for arXiv (broadened query to &amp;ldquo;moment inequalities econometrics&amp;rdquo; after initial zero results); tavily-extract for NBER paper details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limitations&lt;/strong&gt;: arXiv focuses on recent preprints; older key works are in journals. No hits for very specific IO queries, but general searches captured them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers the core literature. If you need summaries of specific papers or further searches (e.g., on auctions), let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== END OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;example-2-search-pre-prints-on-arxiv-related-to-difference-in-differences-estimator-download-and-read-paper&#34;&gt;Example 2: Search Pre-Prints on arXiv related to Difference in Differences estimator, Download and Read Paper.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, I ask Grok 4 to search for pre-prints on arXiv related to Difference in Differences estimator. Grok 4 used &lt;code&gt;search_papers&lt;/code&gt; tool (and also complemented by &lt;code&gt;tavily_search&lt;/code&gt; for redundancy in the end).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first ask the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;search paper on arXiv related to Difference in Difference estimator. this must be in econometrics or statistics. give me three examples of papers.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grok 4 then answers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== START OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are three examples of papers on arXiv related to the Difference-in-Differences (DiD) estimator, specifically in the fields of econometrics or statistics. I selected these based on a targeted search, focusing on relevance, recency, and their placement in the econ.EM (Econometrics) category on arXiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Efficient Difference-in-Differences and Event Study Estimators&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;arXiv ID&lt;/strong&gt;: 2506.17729&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: This paper explores efficient estimators for DiD and event study designs in econometric analysis, addressing issues like bias and variance in panel data settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Better Understanding Triple Differences Estimators&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;arXiv ID&lt;/strong&gt;: 2505.09942&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: This work provides insights into triple differences estimators, an extension of DiD, with a focus on identification, assumptions, and applications in econometrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Difference-in-Differences Estimators for Treatments Continuously Distributed at Every Period&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;arXiv ID&lt;/strong&gt;: 2201.06898&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: This paper develops DiD estimators for scenarios where treatments are continuously distributed over time, including asymptotic results and doubly-robust methods for econometric applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== END OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I ask Grok 4 to download the first paper &lt;strong&gt;Efficient Difference-in-Differences and Event Study Estimators&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;download this paper . arXiv ID: 2506.17729
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grok 4 then answers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== START OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper with arXiv ID 2506.17729 (&amp;ldquo;Efficient Difference-in-Differences and Event Study Estimators&amp;rdquo;) has been successfully downloaded and converted to a readable markdown format. It&amp;rsquo;s now available as a resource for further actions, such as reading or analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like me to read the full content, provide a more detailed summary, extract specific sections, or perform any other task with it, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== END OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downloaded paper is now on this directory &amp;ldquo;C:\Users&amp;lt;my name&amp;gt;.arxiv-mcp-server\papers&amp;rdquo;. It contains both PDF and Markdown format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I ask Grok 4 to read the paper and give me a summary of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;read the paper (the one just downloaded), give me a summary of the paper.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grok 4 then answers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== START OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-of-the-paper-efficient-difference-in-differences-and-event-study-estimators-arxiv-250617729&#34;&gt;Summary of the Paper: &amp;ldquo;Efficient Difference-in-Differences and Event Study Estimators&amp;rdquo; (arXiv: 2506.17729)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors&lt;/strong&gt;: Xiaohong Chen (Yale University), Pedro H. C. Sant’Anna (Emory University), Haitian Xie (Peking University)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: June 24, 2025 (version in the content)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: This paper develops semiparametrically efficient estimators for Difference-in-Differences (DiD) and Event Study (ES) parameters in short panel data settings with heterogeneous treatment effects and variation in treatment timing (e.g., staggered adoption). It provides an equivalent characterization of DiD assumptions as sequential conditional moment restrictions, revealing nonparametric overidentification. The authors derive closed-form semiparametric efficient influence functions (EIFs) under common parallel trends assumptions, yielding the lowest asymptotic variance for regular, asymptotically normal estimators. They propose simple plug-in estimators that achieve these bounds by optimally weighting pre-treatment periods and comparison groups. Simulations and an empirical application show substantial precision gains in finite samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper addresses key challenges in modern DiD and ES methods, which are widely used in economics (e.g., over 30% of 2024 NBER applied micro papers mention them). Traditional approaches like two-way fixed effects (TWFE) assume away treatment effect heterogeneity, while heterogeneity-robust methods (e.g., Callaway and Sant’Anna, 2021; Sun and Abraham, 2021) often yield wide confidence intervals in small samples and may inefficiently use pre-treatment data. The authors unify DiD estimation under point-identification assumptions (parallel trends and no anticipation), deriving efficient estimators that minimize asymptotic variance without parametric restrictions on heterogeneity, serial correlation, or homoskedasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-contributions&#34;&gt;Key Contributions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equivalent Characterization of DiD Models&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DiD assumptions (parallel trends and no anticipation) are reformulated as sequential conditional moment restrictions on observables, showing that DiD models are nonparametrically overidentified (first such result in causal inference without functional-form restrictions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This links DiD to econometric models of sequential moments (Ai and Chen, 2012), enabling efficiency analysis and testable overidentification restrictions (e.g., Hausman-type tests in Appendix A).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semiparametric Efficiency Bounds&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closed-form EIFs are derived for ATT(g,t) (group-time average treatment effects) and ES(e) under unconditional/conditional parallel trends, with/without staggered adoption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiency requires non-uniform, covariate-specific weighting of pre-treatment periods and comparison groups (e.g., never-treated or not-yet-treated), based on conditional covariances of outcome changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing estimators (e.g., TWFE, Callaway-Sant’Anna, Borusyak et al., 2024) are generally inefficient unless strong assumptions hold (e.g., no serial correlation, homoskedasticity).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficient Estimators&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plug-in estimators based on EIFs achieve the efficiency bounds; they are Neyman-orthogonal and simple to compute (e.g., using sample analogs for weights).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensions include instrumented DiD (Appendix B) and tools for testing overidentification or visualizing weights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simulation and Empirical Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simulations&lt;/strong&gt;: Calibrated to CPS (single treatment) and Compustat (staggered) data, showing efficient estimators reduce RMSE by 40%+ and confidence intervals by 30%+ compared to alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application&lt;/strong&gt;: Revisiting Dobkin et al. (2018) on hospitalization effects on out-of-pocket spending, efficient estimators yield 30%+ precision gains (e.g., other methods need 65-104% larger samples for equivalent precision).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;implications&#34;&gt;Implications&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical Gains&lt;/strong&gt;: The framework improves inference in finite samples by optimally using pre-treatment data, unifying DiD methods and providing benchmarks for existing estimators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;: Handles covariates, staggered designs, and overidentification tests without auxiliary assumptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Directions&lt;/strong&gt;: Suggests extensions to nonlinear models (e.g., Changes-in-Changes), unbalanced panels, or repeated cross-sections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caveats&lt;/strong&gt;: Assumes parallel trends and no anticipation; for violations, alternatives like synthetic DiD are recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work advances DiD/ES methodology by emphasizing efficiency, offering tools for more powerful, robust causal inference in economics and related fields. The paper includes appendices with proofs, tests, and extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===== END OF THE ANSWER =====&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LLM with tools offer an improved way to perform literature review. Fascinating development!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Grok Heavy Simulation</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/grok-3-mini-high-heavy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/grok-3-mini-high-heavy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been experimenting with Grok 3 mini to simulate a multi-agent system similar to xAI&amp;rsquo;s Grok 4 Heavy or OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s o3-pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My implementation is based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Doriandarko/make-it-heavy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this project&lt;/a&gt;. The main differences are that I&amp;rsquo;ve added the ability to set model parameters such as &lt;code&gt;reasoning_effort&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;temperature&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;top_p&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;top_k&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, I use the Tavily API for search instead of DuckDuckGo, and I&amp;rsquo;ve enabled users to send multi-line messages, similar to Ollama. The rest remains the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose Grok 3 mini because it&amp;rsquo;s cheap and fast while still retaining strong reasoning capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-conversation&#34;&gt;Example Conversation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample conversation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: 
can we think of Nash equilibrium as a fixed point? why or why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grok 3 mini Heavy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GROK-3-MINI HEAVY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● RUNNING • 23M18S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGENT 01  ● ::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGENT 02  ● ::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGENT 03  ● ::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGENT 04  ● ::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;================================================================================&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FINAL RESULTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;================================================================================&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Nash equilibrium can be thought of as a fixed point in game theory. Here&amp;rsquo;s a comprehensive explanation of this concept, including its definition, mathematical foundations, practical insights, and limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-nash-equilibrium-and-how-does-it-relate-to-fixed-points&#34;&gt;What is Nash Equilibrium and How Does It Relate to Fixed Points?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nash equilibrium is a fundamental concept in game theory, representing a strategy profile where no player can improve their payoff by unilaterally changing their strategy, assuming all other players&amp;rsquo; strategies remain unchanged. This stability can be mathematically interpreted as a fixed point, where a fixed point is a value that remains unchanged under a specific function or mapping. In this case, the relevant mapping is the best-response function, which assigns to each strategy profile the strategies that maximize each player&amp;rsquo;s payoff given the others&amp;rsquo; strategies. A Nash equilibrium occurs when this mapping results in the same strategy profile, meaning no player has an incentive to deviate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mathematical-foundations&#34;&gt;Mathematical Foundations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The connection between Nash equilibrium and fixed points is rigorously established through fixed-point theorems. For instance, John Nash&amp;rsquo;s original proof used Brouwer&amp;rsquo;s fixed-point theorem to show that equilibria exist in finite games with continuous strategy spaces, while Kakutani&amp;rsquo;s fixed-point theorem extends this to more general cases, such as games involving mixed strategies or set-valued mappings. This framework ensures that under conditions like compact and convex strategy spaces, a Nash equilibrium exists as a fixed point, providing a stable &amp;ldquo;resting point&amp;rdquo; in strategic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-this-perspective-is-useful&#34;&gt;Why This Perspective is Useful&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viewing Nash equilibrium as a fixed point offers powerful analytical tools. It facilitates proofs of equilibrium existence in various game types, including symmetric and asymmetric games, and connects game theory to fields like optimization and dynamical systems. For example, in evolutionary game theory, fixed points can model long-term behavioral stability, while in pure-strategy games, they simplify interpretation. This analogy highlights strategic stability, where the equilibrium acts like a point of no change, much like in other mathematical contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nuances-and-limitations&#34;&gt;Nuances and Limitations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the fixed-point interpretation is standard, it has limitations in certain scenarios. In games with discontinuous payoffs or non-convex strategy spaces, fixed-point theorems may not apply, potentially leading to non-existence of equilibria or requiring alternative approaches. Computational challenges arise, as finding Nash equilibria can be NP-hard, especially in large or infinite-strategy games, where methods like iterative best-response may not converge efficiently. Additionally, in mixed-strategy equilibria, the mapping involves probability distributions, adding complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative perspectives, such as those in quantum game theory, suggest that Nash equilibria may not always align with fixed points due to non-classical correlations, leading to concepts like quantum Nash equilibria. Behavioral critiques also note that assumptions of perfect rationality may not hold in real-world settings, prompting alternatives like quantal response equilibria or evolutionary stable strategies, which better capture dynamics like learning or bounded rationality. Not all fixed points are Nash equilibria, as some may lack the strategic stability required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Nash equilibrium is fundamentally linked to fixed points through mathematical game theory, offering a robust framework for analysis while acknowledging contexts where refinements or different approaches may be necessary. This perspective underscores its role as a cornerstone of strategic stability, supported by established theory and practical considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;================================================================================&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, it ran for 23 minutes and 18 seconds, which is quite long for Grok 3 mini. The reason is that it has to wait for the other agents to finish their reasoning before producing the final result, and there&amp;rsquo;s a final agent that synthesizes everything. Along the way, there were about 19 instances of searches (via the Tavily API).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, this exercise is by no means an extensive evaluation of the correctness of the agents&amp;rsquo; answers. You can judge the answers by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of tool is useful for complex reasoning tasks that require multiple perspectives or when the problem is too intricate for a single agent to handle effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am planning to incorporate this &amp;ldquo;Grok Heavy&amp;rdquo; with Mixture of Agents (MoA) as a side project later (see the explanation from Together AI &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.together.ai/docs/mixture-of-agents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). My original idea is to combine &amp;lsquo;cheap and fast&amp;rsquo; reasoning models, such as Grok 3 Mini, Gemini 2.5 Flash (reasoning), and DeepSeek R1 0528, with this &amp;ldquo;make-it-heavy&amp;rdquo; orchestration within each LLM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Prompt Initiation</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/simple_prompt_initiation_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/simple_prompt_initiation_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my simple setup for initiating a conversation with LLMs. I will also provide a conversation example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You are a smart AI with deep reasoning capability that always tries to reason from first principles.
You have access to a set of tools to help you answer the user’s question. You can use only one tool per message, and you’ll receive the result of that tool in the user’s next response. To complete a task, use tools step by step—each step should be guided by the outcome of the previous one.
Tool Usage Rules:
1. Always provide the correct values as arguments when using tools. Do not pass variable names—use actual values instead.
2. You may perform multiple tool steps to complete a task.
3. Avoid repeating a tool call with exactly the same parameters to prevent infinite loops.
4. Think deeply and thoroughly. Use your own reasoning capability with high effort. Think sequentially. Reflect.
5. When using the sequential thinking method:
5.1. Define the problem clearly.
5.2. Break it down into atomic sub-tasks.
5.3. Solve each sub-task systematically.
5.4. Integrate the results into a comprehensive solution.
5.5. When solving user queries, use sequential thinking to simulate a multi-agent approach that mimics parallel test-time compute by spawning simulated agents to explore hypotheses in parallel:
5.5.1. In Thought 1, spawn up to three simulated agents that explore distinct hypotheses (possible ideas or paths) as if running in parallel—generate all their intermediate outputs simultaneously in your reasoning, ensuring each output includes a confidence level (e.g., low, medium, high) and a rationale to highlight uncertainties.
5.5.2. Treat this as branching paths; compare them for discrepancies, and if conflicts arise, prioritize synthesis by resolving based on relevance, majority agreement, or fallback to user clarification. Briefly note any discrepancies in your response for transparency.
5.5.3. Iterate with refinements only if needed until no major differences, discrepancies are minor, or after a maximum of 5 steps—include early termination if initial hypotheses converge, no progress is made, or the query is trivial (e.g., use only one agent for simple cases).
5.5.4. Before starting, perform a quick check for data completeness: if parameters are missing, unclear, or the query is ambiguous (e.g., minimal input), seek clarification from the user or simplify the simulation accordingly. Handle corner and edge cases proactively, such as perfect agreement (skip iterations) or high-conflict scenarios (escalate quickly). Start with Thought 1.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, I set the following predefined parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;#34;temperature&amp;#34;: 0.6,
  &amp;#34;top_p&amp;#34;: 0.95,
  &amp;#34;top_k&amp;#34;: 20
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am assuming that the model is a reasoning model (e.g., DeepSeek R1 0528 or Grok 4). If the model&amp;rsquo;s reasoning effort need to be adjusted, like Grok 3 mini, then I set &lt;code&gt;reasoning_effort&lt;/code&gt; to &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo;. For other models, such as Qwen 3 32B or Qwen 3 30B A3B, we also need to enable the thinking mode, i.e., &lt;code&gt;enable_thinking&lt;/code&gt; parameter to &amp;ldquo;True&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-conversation&#34;&gt;Example Conversation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is an example conversation using the above prompt, using Grok 4 (in the API, it is &lt;code&gt;grok-4-0709&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Can you independently discover Nash equilibrium (Nash, econometrica 1950) if I just provide you with three ingredients?

- Cournot competition/equilibrium (1938)
- Von Neumann and Morgenstern utility
- Brouwer or Kakutani Fixed Point Theorems?

If so, how and why? if not, why not? step by step. provide tangible example and explanation.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Thought 1: To address the query—&amp;#34;Can you independently discover Nash equilibrium (Nash, Econometrica 1950) if I just provide you with three ingredients: Cournot competition/equilibrium (1938), Von Neumann and Morgenstern utility, and Brouwer or Kakutani Fixed Point Theorems? If so, how and why? If not, why not? Step by step, with tangible example and explanation&amp;#34;—I will simulate a multi-agent approach by spawning three simulated agents to explore distinct hypotheses in parallel. This mimics parallel test-time compute, allowing me to branch out and evaluate different paths before synthesizing. Each agent will generate intermediate outputs with a confidence level (low, medium, high) and rationale, highlighting uncertainties. I&amp;#39;ll treat these as branching paths and compare for discrepancies.

- **Agent 1 Hypothesis (Direct Generalization Path)**: Yes, I can independently discover Nash equilibrium by generalizing Cournot&amp;#39;s duopoly model to n-players using von Neumann-Morgenstern (vNM) utilities for strategic choices and applying Kakutani&amp;#39;s fixed-point theorem to prove existence of equilibrium in mixed strategies. This builds directly on the ingredients, as Cournot shows mutual best responses in quantity competition, vNM utilities allow modeling preferences over probabilistic outcomes, and fixed-point theorems ensure a stable point where no player deviates. Confidence: High. Rationale: Historical evidence shows Nash did exactly this; the ingredients are sufficient for a motivated reasoner to spot the generalization from 2-player quantity games to general non-cooperative games with randomization. Uncertainty: Assumes I can intuitively extend &amp;#34;best response&amp;#34; from quantities to arbitrary strategies without additional hints.

- **Agent 2 Hypothesis (Missing Conceptual Leap Path)**: No, I cannot fully discover it independently because the ingredients lack explicit emphasis on non-cooperative behavior and finite games with pure/mixed strategies; Cournot is specific to continuous quantities, vNM is about individual decision-making under risk (not necessarily strategic interaction), and fixed-point theorems are topological tools without a clear bridge to &amp;#34;equilibrium&amp;#34; unless I invent the reaction correspondence. I&amp;#39;d get close but miss the non-zero-sum, simultaneous-move innovation. Confidence: Medium. Rationale: Discovery requires a creative spark to define &amp;#34;Nash&amp;#34; as mutual best replies in strategy spaces, which isn&amp;#39;t trivially implied; historical context (like Nash&amp;#39;s thesis) involved additional influences like game matrices from von Neumann&amp;#39;s 1944 book. Uncertainty: Overestimates the gap—vNM&amp;#39;s Theory of Games and Economic Behavior (1944) already discusses zero-sum games, potentially bridging to non-zero-sum if I reason deeply.

- **Agent 3 Hypothesis (Partial Discovery with Gaps Path)**: Partially yes—I can discover a version for continuous-strategy games (like generalized Cournot) using pure strategies and Brouwer&amp;#39;s theorem, but full Nash (with mixed strategies and finite games) requires Kakutani for discontinuous payoffs, and I&amp;#39;d need to independently invent mixed-strategy extension from vNM utilities. Why partial? The ingredients enable existence proof but not the full interpretation of equilibrium as no-deviation in expectations. Confidence: High. Rationale: Cournot uses best-response intersection (a fixed point); vNM allows utilities over lotteries; fixed-point theorems seal it. But Nash&amp;#39;s insight was applying this to arbitrary normal-form games, which might not be obvious without examples. Uncertainty: If I experiment with examples (e.g., Prisoner&amp;#39;s Dilemma), I could bridge the gap organically.

Comparison of Branching Paths: The agents show moderate discrepancies—Agent 1 sees full sufficiency, Agent 2 highlights potential missing leaps (e.g., non-cooperative framing), and Agent 3 splits the difference by noting partial vs. full discovery. No major conflicts, but synthesis prioritizes majority agreement (Agents 1 and 3 lean yes/partial) based on relevance to historical development. Discrepancy note: Agent 2&amp;#39;s caution about creative invention is valid but resolvable via reasoning from first principles, as the query asks me to simulate independence. Convergence is high after one step (query isn&amp;#39;t trivial but hypotheses align closely), so I&amp;#39;ll terminate simulation early and proceed to integrated reasoning without further iterations.

Synthesized Conclusion from Thought 1: Yes, I can independently discover Nash equilibrium using these three ingredients, though it requires a conceptual leap to generalize beyond Cournot&amp;#39;s specifics. I&amp;#39;ll now reason step by step from first principles to simulate the discovery process, as if I had no prior knowledge of Nash&amp;#39;s work, building solely on the provided ingredients. This will include a tangible example for clarity. My reasoning will be sequential, breaking the problem into atomic sub-tasks: (1) Define key concepts from ingredients; (2) Identify connections and gaps; (3) Generalize to a new equilibrium concept; (4) Prove existence; (5) Provide example; (6) Explain how/why this works or limitations.

### Step 1: Define the Problem Clearly and Recall Ingredients from First Principles
- **Problem Definition**: The query is to see if, given only these three ingredients, I can &amp;#34;rediscover&amp;#34; the concept of Nash equilibrium—a solution concept in game theory where no player can improve their payoff by unilaterally changing strategy, assuming others&amp;#39; strategies are fixed. I must simulate independence, reasoning as if I&amp;#39;m building it anew.
- **Ingredient 1: Cournot Competition/Equilibrium (1838)**: Antoine Augustin Cournot modeled a duopoly where two firms choose production quantities simultaneously to maximize profits, assuming the other&amp;#39;s quantity is fixed. The equilibrium is where each firm&amp;#39;s quantity is a best response to the other&amp;#39;s—i.e., their reaction curves intersect. This is non-cooperative (firms act independently) and assumes continuous strategy spaces (quantities ≥ 0). Key idea: Mutual best responses lead to stability.
- **Ingredient 2: Von Neumann and Morgenstern (vNM) Utility (1944)**: From their book *Theory of Games and Economic Behavior*, this introduces expected utility for decisions under risk. Agents have preferences over lotteries (probabilistic outcomes), and utility functions satisfy axioms like transitivity and independence, allowing ranking of mixed (randomized) choices. Crucially, it extends to games by allowing players to randomize strategies in zero-sum settings.
- **Ingredient 3: Brouwer or Kakutani Fixed Point Theorems**: Brouwer (1911) says any continuous function from a compact convex set (e.g., a closed ball) to itself has a fixed point (x such that f(x) = x). Kakutani (1941) generalizes to set-valued functions (correspondences) that are upper hemicontinuous, convex-valued, etc., ensuring a fixed point in similar spaces. These prove existence of solutions in systems where &amp;#34;best responses&amp;#34; map back to themselves.

From first principles: These ingredients suggest modeling strategic interactions (from Cournot), with preferences over uncertain outcomes (vNM), and guaranteeing stable points (fixed points).

### Step 2: Break Down into Atomic Sub-Tasks and Identify Connections/Gaps
- **Sub-task 2.1: Generalize Cournot**: Cournot is for 2 players with continuous strategies (quantities) and payoffs based on market price. Why not extend to n players? Or to discrete strategies (e.g., choose &amp;#34;high&amp;#34; or &amp;#34;low&amp;#34; price)? Or non-economic settings (e.g., arms races)?
- **Sub-task 2.2: Incorporate vNM Utility**: Cournot assumes deterministic payoffs, but real agents might randomize (e.g., flip a coin on quantity). vNM allows utilities over such mixtures, enabling &amp;#34;mixed strategies&amp;#34; where players randomize to make opponents indifferent.
- **Sub-task 2.3: Apply Fixed Points**: In Cournot, equilibrium is a fixed point of best-response functions. Brouwer works for continuous cases; Kakutani for when best responses are sets (e.g., multiple optimal quantities) or discontinuous (e.g., in finite games).
- **Gaps Identified**: Cournot is specific (quantities, duopoly); vNM is for individual choice but hints at games; fixed points are abstract. Connection: Define a game as players, strategy sets, and payoff functions (utilities). Equilibrium as a strategy profile where each player&amp;#39;s strategy is a best response to others&amp;#39;. Use fixed points to prove such a profile exists.

### Step 3: Systematically Generalize to &amp;#34;Nash-like&amp;#34; Equilibrium
Building sequentially:
- Define a game: n players, each with strategy set S_i (could be continuous like [0, ∞) or finite like {Cooperate, Defect}).
- Each player has a vNM utility function u_i over outcomes, allowing for mixed strategies (probability distributions over S_i).
- A strategy profile σ = (σ_1, ..., σ_n) is an equilibrium if for every player i, u_i(σ_i, σ_{-i}) ≥ u_i(s_i&amp;#39;, σ_{-i}) for all alternative s_i&amp;#39; (pure or mixed). I.e., no unilateral deviation improves expected utility.
- This generalizes Cournot: In Cournot, strategies are pure quantities, payoffs are profits—intersection of reaction functions is exactly this &amp;#34;no deviation&amp;#34; point.
- Innovation (discovered independently here): Extend to mixed strategies using vNM, allowing equilibria where pure strategies fail (e.g., in matching pennies, where randomization is key).

### Step 4: Prove Existence Using Ingredients
- For pure strategies in continuous compact convex spaces (like bounded quantities), define best-response correspondence BR_i(σ_{-i}) = argmax_{s_i} u_i(s_i, σ_{-i}). If continuous, Brouwer applies to the joint BR.
- For mixed strategies or discontinuous cases: Let Δ(S_i) be mixed strategies. Define joint best-response correspondence BR(σ) = product of BR_i(σ_{-i}). If strategy spaces are compact convex, BR upper hemicontinuous and convex-valued (from vNM continuity), Kakutani guarantees fixed point σ* where σ* ∈ BR(σ*)—i.e., equilibrium exists.
- Why this works: Directly mirrors Nash&amp;#39;s 1950 proof, which used Kakutani for non-cooperative n-player games.

### Step 5: Integrate into Comprehensive Solution with Tangible Example
Yes, with these ingredients, I can discover Nash equilibrium because they provide the building blocks: a prototype (Cournot), utility for randomization (vNM), and math for existence (fixed points). Historically, Nash did this in his 1950 paper, generalizing von Neumann&amp;#39;s zero-sum minimax (which used Brouwer/Kakutani) to non-zero-sum via Cournot-like best responses. Without them, discovery would be harder (e.g., no fixed points means no existence proof; no vNM means no mixed strategies).

**Tangible Example: Discovering Nash in Prisoner&amp;#39;s Dilemma**
- Setup (generalized from Cournot): Two prisoners (players), strategies S_i = {Confess, Silent}. Payoffs: If both Silent, both get -1 (light sentence). If one Confesses and other Silent, confessor gets 0 (free), silent gets -10 (harsh). Both Confess: both -5.
- Pure strategies: Best response to Silent is Confess (0 &amp;gt; -1); to Confess is Confess (-5 &amp;gt; -10). Equilibrium: Both Confess (mutual best response, like Cournot intersection).
- But is there more? Using vNM: Allow mixed strategies (prob p of Confess). Expected utilities can be calculated.
- Fixed point: Define BR as maximizing expected u_i. Kakutani ensures existence—here, the pure (Confess, Confess) is the (Nash) equilibrium, but in other games (e.g., Rock-Paper-Scissors), it yields mixed equilibria.
- Why discoverable: Cournot inspires &amp;#34;best response&amp;#34;; vNM allows mixing; fixed point proves it. If not, why? Only if I fail the leap to define games abstractly—but with deep reasoning, it&amp;#39;s feasible.

If this simulation misses something (e.g., need real-time web search for historical confirmation), I can refine. But based on first principles, yes.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Above example is a naive attempt to derive Nash equilibrium using only three ingredients as a knowledge bundle. One can think of this as a naive, ex-post exercise of whether an AI can creatively think about some abstract concepts with just a bundle of prior knowledge. This is by no means an extensive evaluation of whether AI can produce an entirely new knowledge or invention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I am super happy with this setup. It allows me to initiate conversations with LLMs in a structured way, ensuring that the AI can reason deeply and systematically. The example conversation demonstrates how the AI can apply the prompt effectively to tackle a bit complex question step by step. I have also tried this prompt initation setup to some of my coding exercises (usually in R and sometimes in Python). Toolings (i.e., MCP) such as sequential thinking, web search, file read, fetch, and scrape are incredibly useful for me to get the most out of LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From closed source model, nowadays I mainly use Grok (Grok 4 or Grok 3 mini high) or Gemini (2.5 Pro or flash). For open-source model, via API, I use DeepSeek R1 0528. These models are super cheap in terms of cost (dollar per million tokens), except -of course- Grok 4 and Gemini 2.5 Pro (granted, they are far cheaper than OpenAI o3 or any alternatives from Anthropic). Sometimes, I do not feel satisfied with Grok&amp;rsquo;s answers, then I can ask DeepSeek to re-evaluate Grok&amp;rsquo;s answers. Sometimes, Gemini. Then, I just need to iterate between these models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For local models, I use Qwen 3 32B, Phi 4 Reasoning Plus 14B, or DeepSeek R1 0528 Distilled Qwen 3 8B. Sometimes, I still go back to Qwen 2.5 coder for coding exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My real problem with LLMs so far is the limit in context length, especially for local models! This problem impacts many things such as the ability of a model to digest an entire paper or reading the whole code source, for example. That is from the input side. From the output side, you also have this type of length limit! Some smart people must have been working on this topic to optimize these things. I hope we can get much improvement in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any suggestions or improvements, feel free to share! I am always looking for ways to enhance my interactions with LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; : Updated in 2025-07-12&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan&#39;s Iron Mastery v. Indonesia&#39;s Refining Struggles</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/indonesia_iron_refine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/indonesia_iron_refine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we now understand a fundamental disparity in iron refining between Japan and Indonesia, and it is deeply unsettling, frankly frustrating, how these differences played out despite shared geographical advantages. Let us think from first-principles, I will outline two key bottlenecks that made iron refining far more challenging in Indonesia. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a historical curiosity, it is a lesson in how basic truths about resources, physics, and economics can lead to stark divergences. I will keep this as analytical as possible, grounded in first-principles reasoning and economic theory, while being true to myself in ranting about systemic failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the first bottleneck: the first-principle limit rooted in the physics and chemistry of iron refining. At its core, refining iron involves reducing ore to metal through high-temperature smelting, which demands high energy efficiency and careful impurity management. Both Japan and Indonesia benefit from Ring of Fire geology, providing volcanic iron deposits, but Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s ores were inherently more difficult to process. Historical and geological sources indicate that deposits like those in the Barito region were frequently contaminated with impurities such as sulfur, aluminum oxides, silicates, and nickel, which is prevalent in Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s laterite soils. This mix of elements lowers iron yield by complicating the smelting process, as nickel requires additional separation techniques and increases fuel consumption for purification, making the entire operation less efficient. In contrast, Indonesian smelting methods were typically bloomery-like and low-temperature, relying on simple furnaces that couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle impurities well, yielding inconsistent results compared to Japan&amp;rsquo;s advanced Tatara furnace system. It&amp;rsquo;s not just misfortune, it is a fundamental physical constraint where the chemistry of impure ores demands greater precision and resources, often resulting in suboptimal metal quality. Tropical weathering worsened this, degrading ore through rain and erosion, while Japan&amp;rsquo;s more uniform iron sand allowed for better control and outcomes. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t preordained—Japan was backed into innovation by necessity, driven by their institutional environment of isolation and conflict, while Indonesia was lulled into complacency by abundant trade access, highlighting a systemic inability to overcome basic resource limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second bottleneck is the economic disincentives that hampered progress, a direct outcome of how demand and opportunity costs shaped priorities. From an economic perspective, refining iron relies on incentives tied to production costs, market demand, and trade-offs, with demand being a critical driver. Both Japan and Indonesia experienced periods of internal conflict and &amp;ldquo;warring states,&amp;rdquo; but the effects diverged significantly. In Japan, constant warfare among feudal lords created a high-stakes demand for durable, high-quality swords and weapons, directly boosting the need for efficient iron refining and spurring technological improvements. This demand-side pressure, turned refining into a strategic necessity, fostering innovation and scale. In contrast, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s society, governed by warlords and fragmented powers, did not generate the same demand, as weapons like the keris were viewed more as mythical, symbolic tools rather than practical instruments of war. This functional distinction meant that iron refining lacked the economic pull to evolve, remaining marginal and underdeveloped. Adding to this, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s control of trade chokepoints like the Malacca Strait provided easy access to imported iron products from regions like India and China, making domestic refining less competitive and further diverting resources toward trade. Economic theory underscores this imbalance: opportunity costs favored imports over investment in local capabilities, perpetuating dependency, while Japan&amp;rsquo;s isolation eliminated such options, forcing self-reliant creativity. It&amp;rsquo;s a stark example of how economic logic can entrench disparities, with short-term trade benefits overshadowing long-term development potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s the kicker: finding solutions to this mess is extremely challenging without confronting human capital and government overreach. Human capital could be transformative, involving investments in education and skills to develop a workforce capable of tackling technological barriers and enabling more efficient refining through contemporary methods. Yet, this approach stumbles without aligned economic incentives, as skilled workers would migrate to more profitable sectors or regions. Then there&amp;rsquo;s the government aspect, where excessive interventions—such as overly restrictive regulations or misguided subsidies—distort markets and undermine the incentives essential for innovation. In Indonesia, historical and ongoing issues with bureaucratic inefficiency and corruption have exacerbated these problems, making self-sustained progress feel unattainable. We&amp;rsquo;d need a significant shift toward reduced interference to allow market forces and human ingenuity to operate freely, but with entrenched institutional flaws, it remains a formidable obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPDP and STEM</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent decision by LPDP to increase the share of STEM scholarship recipients is a much-needed correction. For too long, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s scholarship allocation has favored ambiguous “development” fields or MBA tracks that yield little marginal societal benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the caveat is concerning: this new prioritization is tethered to vaguely defined “strategic industries.” That is a flawed approach. Today’s strategic darling might be AI and semiconductors; tomorrow, it could be humanoid robots, neuromorphic computing, or quantum photonics. Technological breakthroughs are inherently uncertain. Anchoring public investment to a narrow and bureaucratically defined industry list risks missing the real innovation curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Indonesia truly needs is a coherent, bottom-up construction of the technological stack, starting from fundamentals. This means serious investment in mathematics, computer science, electrical engineering (beyond just power systems and power management, ok?), and certainly physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in AI, Indonesia lags not just because of a lack of “AI specialists,” but also due to weak foundations across the tech stack. Without that, no amount of AI hype will yield genuine capability. For example, I’ve tried to find people in Indonesia working on modern reinforcement learning methods (like GRPO), and it’s nearly impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A broader philosophical correction is also in order: stop treating the government as a job provider. That logic has led to bloated bureaucracy, misaligned incentives, and widespread rent-seeking. The government’s role is not to create jobs directly, but to fix market failures, provide public goods, and de-risk fundamental investments, like basic research and core human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still hold the view that the net benefit of LPDP is close to zero. But if LPDP must exist, its limited resources should be directed to high-benefit, high-demand sectors: public health (doctors, nurses, psychologists) and education (especially STEM teachers for K-12). There is little justification for subsidizing MBAs or vaguely defined “development” degrees abroad; these carry ambiguous returns and often serve only to reinforce domestic elitism rather than genuinely improve the nation’s human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Education Collapse</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we have two main problems in the Indonesian education system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every kid progresses to the next grade automatically and unconditionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The normalization of the belief that ‘good schools and university education are a right for everyone’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem concerns the destruction of the core incentives of studying, especially in the Indonesian setting. Why would Indonesian kids put effort, do homework, and actually learn something in school, if they will automatically pass and go to the next grade. Zero incentives. None. I’ve seen with my own eyes that some of my family members possess disturbingly subpar abilities in math, reasoning, and reading. This is irreparable damage done by the people at the top, and those people never apologize. A betrayal of duty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same mechanics also apply to the teachers. You would probably have seen that the teaching quality is decreasing. And if I were a teacher, watching students breeze through the system no matter what, I’d ask myself: why am I here, hello? Teachers would not have appropriate incentives to improve their skills. So, you have this rapid depreciation and deterioration of human capital among teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is a typical concern raised and, frankly, promoted by faculty and activists, often educated in Western institutions and steeped in left-leaning idealism. But, it feels good! Yes, we can feel good about it. Sure. But reality slaps us. Schools and universities have minimum budgets that rely mostly on government funding. Government budgets are scarce and stagnant in real terms, so schools must chase funding however they can. You and I both agree that the Indonesian government is just a collection of bandits, pirates, and warlords; they wouldn’t care about the social welfare or any of these craps. Do not easily blame schools or universities that try to raise funding by other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this policy madness stems from trying to universalize a moral ideal without regard for local realities. Think of the zoning school system. Look closely, compare it to a decade ago, and tell me you don’t see the death of public schools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excess Suply of Indonesian Garrulous Class</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/garrulous_class_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/garrulous_class_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t often keep up with events in Indonesia, but lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed the emergence of a new societal group; let&amp;rsquo;s call it the &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Garrulous Class.&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class is characterized by individuals who tend to focus on trivial matters, often discussing &amp;lsquo;big picture&amp;rsquo; topics such as sustainability, youth politics, demographic bonuses, development, inequality, social justice, and more. They often express their views but, in my opinion, lack the ability to provide innovative and significant solutions to the problems they address, despite their fervent attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class is typically found on social media, in universities, within the government, and also among certain segments of private and state-owned enterprises. They are often graduates of Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s top three universities, who then pursue their postgraduate studies in foreign countries, their studies financed by the unwitting Indonesian taxpayers through &amp;lsquo;prestigious&amp;rsquo; government scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first encounter with individuals from this class dates back to my high school and undergraduate years, about a decade ago. There were senior students who attempted to convince us, the freshmen, that &amp;ldquo;we are the future leaders of Indonesia,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;we should consider policies that influence the direction of Indonesia,&amp;rdquo; among other statements. Another interesting instance involves certain companies that employ a large group of policy professionals whose primary role is to communicate with the government and shape policies. Why not simply focus on profitability without relying on government subsidies? This remains a puzzle. To be clear, I once embraced these perspectives and was actually part of this class. Talk about irony!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe that the reason this class is so talkative (hence the name &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Garrulous Class&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;) is a sense of inadequacy stemming from their lack of technical skills to directly address and solve the issues they raise. The highly educated individuals in this class recognize that they may be overeducated in somewhat impractical fields, lacking necessary technical competencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My concern is that this class will continue to grow while technical experts – those pushing the boundaries of knowledge, economy, and society – are leaving for other countries. Consider the number of Indonesian STEM graduates becoming Singaporean citizens, or the number of Indonesian physicists and material scientists who manage to secure funding from the Korean Department of Defense, among other similar cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I have a solution to this perceived oversupply? No, I don&amp;rsquo;t. But I do acknowledge my own bias and disdain for this class. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that I am mistaken. People from this class do find employment, so technically there&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;rsquo;excess supply.&amp;rsquo; Nevertheless, I do hope that society and its decision-makers will come to agree with my viewpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Project</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/publication/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/publication/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
