<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Regi Kusumaatmadja</title>
    <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPDP and STEM</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent decision by LPDP to increase the share of STEM scholarship recipients is a much-needed correction. For too long, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s scholarship allocation has favored ambiguous “development” fields or MBA tracks that yield little marginal societal benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the caveat is concerning: this new prioritization is tethered to vaguely defined “strategic industries.” That is a flawed approach. Today’s strategic darling might be AI and semiconductors; tomorrow, it could be humanoid robots, neuromorphic computing, or quantum photonics. Technological breakthroughs are inherently uncertain. Anchoring public investment to a narrow and bureaucratically defined industry list risks missing the real innovation curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Indonesia truly needs is a coherent, bottom-up construction of the technological stack, starting from fundamentals. This means serious investment in mathematics, computer science, electrical engineering (beyond just power systems and power management, ok?), and certainly physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in AI, Indonesia lags not just because of a lack of “AI specialists,” but also due to weak foundations across the tech stack. Without that, no amount of AI hype will yield genuine capability. For example, I’ve tried to find people in Indonesia working on modern reinforcement learning methods (like GRPO), and it’s nearly impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A broader philosophical correction is also in order: stop treating the government as a job provider. That logic has led to bloated bureaucracy, misaligned incentives, and widespread rent-seeking. The government’s role is not to create jobs directly, but to fix market failures, provide public goods, and de-risk fundamental investments, like basic research and core human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still hold the view that the net benefit of LPDP is close to zero. But if LPDP must exist, its limited resources should be directed to high-benefit, high-demand sectors: public health (doctors, nurses, psychologists) and education (especially STEM teachers for K-12). There is little justification for subsidizing MBAs or vaguely defined “development” degrees abroad; these carry ambiguous returns and often serve only to reinforce domestic elitism rather than genuinely improve the nation’s human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Education Collapse</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we have two main problems in the Indonesian education system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every kid progresses to the next grade automatically and unconditionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The normalization of the belief that ‘good schools and university education are a right for everyone’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem concerns the destruction of the core incentives of studying, especially in the Indonesian setting. Why would Indonesian kids put effort, do homework, and actually learn something in school, if they will automatically pass and go to the next grade. Zero incentives. None. I’ve seen with my own eyes that some of my family members possess disturbingly subpar abilities in math, reasoning, and reading. This is irreparable damage done by the people at the top, and those people never apologize. A betrayal of duty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same mechanics also apply to the teachers. You would probably have seen that the teaching quality is decreasing. And if I were a teacher, watching students breeze through the system no matter what, I’d ask myself: why am I here, hello? Teachers would not have appropriate incentives to improve their skills. So, you have this rapid depreciation and deterioration of human capital among teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is a typical concern raised and, frankly, promoted by faculty and activists, often educated in Western institutions and steeped in left-leaning idealism. But, it feels good! Yes, we can feel good about it. Sure. But reality slaps us. Schools and universities have minimum budgets that rely mostly on government funding. Government budgets are scarce and stagnant in real terms, so schools must chase funding however they can. You and I both agree that the Indonesian government is just a collection of bandits, pirates, and warlords; they wouldn’t care about the social welfare or any of these craps. Do not easily blame schools or universities that try to raise funding by other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this policy madness stems from trying to universalize a moral ideal without regard for local realities. Think of the zoning school system. Look closely, compare it to a decade ago, and tell me you don’t see the death of public schools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
