<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Regi Kusumaatmadja</title>
    <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan&#39;s Iron Mastery v. Indonesia&#39;s Refining Struggles</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/indonesia_iron_refine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/indonesia_iron_refine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we now understand a fundamental disparity in iron refining between Japan and Indonesia, and it is deeply unsettling, frankly frustrating, how these differences played out despite shared geographical advantages. Let us think from first-principles, I will outline two key bottlenecks that made iron refining far more challenging in Indonesia. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a historical curiosity, it is a lesson in how basic truths about resources, physics, and economics can lead to stark divergences. I will keep this as analytical as possible, grounded in first-principles reasoning and economic theory, while being true to myself in ranting about systemic failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the first bottleneck: the first-principle limit rooted in the physics and chemistry of iron refining. At its core, refining iron involves reducing ore to metal through high-temperature smelting, which demands high energy efficiency and careful impurity management. Both Japan and Indonesia benefit from Ring of Fire geology, providing volcanic iron deposits, but Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s ores were inherently more difficult to process. Historical and geological sources indicate that deposits like those in the Barito region were frequently contaminated with impurities such as sulfur, aluminum oxides, silicates, and nickel, which is prevalent in Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s laterite soils. This mix of elements lowers iron yield by complicating the smelting process, as nickel requires additional separation techniques and increases fuel consumption for purification, making the entire operation less efficient. In contrast, Indonesian smelting methods were typically bloomery-like and low-temperature, relying on simple furnaces that couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle impurities well, yielding inconsistent results compared to Japan&amp;rsquo;s advanced Tatara furnace system. It&amp;rsquo;s not just misfortune, it is a fundamental physical constraint where the chemistry of impure ores demands greater precision and resources, often resulting in suboptimal metal quality. Tropical weathering worsened this, degrading ore through rain and erosion, while Japan&amp;rsquo;s more uniform iron sand allowed for better control and outcomes. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t preordained—Japan was backed into innovation by necessity, driven by their institutional environment of isolation and conflict, while Indonesia was lulled into complacency by abundant trade access, highlighting a systemic inability to overcome basic resource limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second bottleneck is the economic disincentives that hampered progress, a direct outcome of how demand and opportunity costs shaped priorities. From an economic perspective, refining iron relies on incentives tied to production costs, market demand, and trade-offs, with demand being a critical driver. Both Japan and Indonesia experienced periods of internal conflict and &amp;ldquo;warring states,&amp;rdquo; but the effects diverged significantly. In Japan, constant warfare among feudal lords created a high-stakes demand for durable, high-quality swords and weapons, directly boosting the need for efficient iron refining and spurring technological improvements. This demand-side pressure, turned refining into a strategic necessity, fostering innovation and scale. In contrast, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s society, governed by warlords and fragmented powers, did not generate the same demand, as weapons like the keris were viewed more as mythical, symbolic tools rather than practical instruments of war. This functional distinction meant that iron refining lacked the economic pull to evolve, remaining marginal and underdeveloped. Adding to this, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s control of trade chokepoints like the Malacca Strait provided easy access to imported iron products from regions like India and China, making domestic refining less competitive and further diverting resources toward trade. Economic theory underscores this imbalance: opportunity costs favored imports over investment in local capabilities, perpetuating dependency, while Japan&amp;rsquo;s isolation eliminated such options, forcing self-reliant creativity. It&amp;rsquo;s a stark example of how economic logic can entrench disparities, with short-term trade benefits overshadowing long-term development potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s the kicker: finding solutions to this mess is extremely challenging without confronting human capital and government overreach. Human capital could be transformative, involving investments in education and skills to develop a workforce capable of tackling technological barriers and enabling more efficient refining through contemporary methods. Yet, this approach stumbles without aligned economic incentives, as skilled workers would migrate to more profitable sectors or regions. Then there&amp;rsquo;s the government aspect, where excessive interventions—such as overly restrictive regulations or misguided subsidies—distort markets and undermine the incentives essential for innovation. In Indonesia, historical and ongoing issues with bureaucratic inefficiency and corruption have exacerbated these problems, making self-sustained progress feel unattainable. We&amp;rsquo;d need a significant shift toward reduced interference to allow market forces and human ingenuity to operate freely, but with entrenched institutional flaws, it remains a formidable obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPDP and STEM</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent decision by LPDP to increase the share of STEM scholarship recipients is a much-needed correction. For too long, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s scholarship allocation has favored ambiguous “development” fields or MBA tracks that yield little marginal societal benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the caveat is concerning: this new prioritization is tethered to vaguely defined “strategic industries.” That is a flawed approach. Today’s strategic darling might be AI and semiconductors; tomorrow, it could be humanoid robots, neuromorphic computing, or quantum photonics. Technological breakthroughs are inherently uncertain. Anchoring public investment to a narrow and bureaucratically defined industry list risks missing the real innovation curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Indonesia truly needs is a coherent, bottom-up construction of the technological stack, starting from fundamentals. This means serious investment in mathematics, computer science, electrical engineering (beyond just power systems and power management, ok?), and certainly physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in AI, Indonesia lags not just because of a lack of “AI specialists,” but also due to weak foundations across the tech stack. Without that, no amount of AI hype will yield genuine capability. For example, I’ve tried to find people in Indonesia working on modern reinforcement learning methods (like GRPO), and it’s nearly impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A broader philosophical correction is also in order: stop treating the government as a job provider. That logic has led to bloated bureaucracy, misaligned incentives, and widespread rent-seeking. The government’s role is not to create jobs directly, but to fix market failures, provide public goods, and de-risk fundamental investments, like basic research and core human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still hold the view that the net benefit of LPDP is close to zero. But if LPDP must exist, its limited resources should be directed to high-benefit, high-demand sectors: public health (doctors, nurses, psychologists) and education (especially STEM teachers for K-12). There is little justification for subsidizing MBAs or vaguely defined “development” degrees abroad; these carry ambiguous returns and often serve only to reinforce domestic elitism rather than genuinely improve the nation’s human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Education Collapse</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we have two main problems in the Indonesian education system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every kid progresses to the next grade automatically and unconditionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The normalization of the belief that ‘good schools and university education are a right for everyone’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem concerns the destruction of the core incentives of studying, especially in the Indonesian setting. Why would Indonesian kids put effort, do homework, and actually learn something in school, if they will automatically pass and go to the next grade. Zero incentives. None. I’ve seen with my own eyes that some of my family members possess disturbingly subpar abilities in math, reasoning, and reading. This is irreparable damage done by the people at the top, and those people never apologize. A betrayal of duty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same mechanics also apply to the teachers. You would probably have seen that the teaching quality is decreasing. And if I were a teacher, watching students breeze through the system no matter what, I’d ask myself: why am I here, hello? Teachers would not have appropriate incentives to improve their skills. So, you have this rapid depreciation and deterioration of human capital among teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is a typical concern raised and, frankly, promoted by faculty and activists, often educated in Western institutions and steeped in left-leaning idealism. But, it feels good! Yes, we can feel good about it. Sure. But reality slaps us. Schools and universities have minimum budgets that rely mostly on government funding. Government budgets are scarce and stagnant in real terms, so schools must chase funding however they can. You and I both agree that the Indonesian government is just a collection of bandits, pirates, and warlords; they wouldn’t care about the social welfare or any of these craps. Do not easily blame schools or universities that try to raise funding by other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this policy madness stems from trying to universalize a moral ideal without regard for local realities. Think of the zoning school system. Look closely, compare it to a decade ago, and tell me you don’t see the death of public schools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
