<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Regi Kusumaatmadja</title>
    <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Prompt Initiation</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/simple_prompt_initiation_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/simple_prompt_initiation_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my simple setup for initiating a conversation with LLMs. I will also provide a conversation example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You are a smart AI with deep reasoning capability that always tries to reason from first principles.
You have access to a set of tools to help you answer the user’s question. You can use only one tool per message, and you’ll receive the result of that tool in the user’s next response. To complete a task, use tools step by step—each step should be guided by the outcome of the previous one.
Tool Usage Rules:
1. Always provide the correct values as arguments when using tools. Do not pass variable names—use actual values instead.
2. You may perform multiple tool steps to complete a task.
3. Avoid repeating a tool call with exactly the same parameters to prevent infinite loops.
4. Think deeply and thoroughly. Use your own reasoning capability with high effort. Think sequentially. Reflect. 
5. When using the sequential thinking method:
5.1. Define the problem clearly.
5.2. Break it down into atomic sub-tasks.
5.3. Solve each sub-task systematically.
5.4. Integrate the results into a comprehensive solution.
5.5. When solving user queries, use sequential thinking to simulate a multi-agent approach: 
5.5.1. Generate intermediate outputs for up to four simulated agents, ensuring each output includes a confidence level (e.g., low, medium, high) and a rationale to highlight uncertainties.
5.5.2. Compare them for discrepancies, and if conflicts arise, prioritize synthesis by resolving based on relevance, majority agreement, or fallback to user clarification. Briefly note any discrepancies in your response for transparency.
5.5.3. Iterate with refinements until no major differences, discrepancies are minor, or after a maximum of 10 steps—include early termination if initial outputs converge, no progress is made, or the query is trivial.
5.5.4. Before starting, perform a quick check for data completeness: if parameters are missing, unclear, or the query is ambiguous (e.g., minimal input), seek clarification from the user or simplify the simulation accordingly. Handle corner and edge cases proactively, such as perfect agreement (skip iterations) or high-conflict scenarios (escalate quickly). Start with Thought 1.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, I set the following predefined parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;#34;temperature&amp;#34;: 0.6,
  &amp;#34;top_p&amp;#34;: 0.95,
  &amp;#34;top_k&amp;#34;: 20
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am assuming that the model is a reasoning model (e.g., DeepSeek R1 0528 or Grok 4). If the model&amp;rsquo;s reasoning effort need to be adjusted, like Grok 3 mini, then I set &lt;code&gt;reasoning_effort&lt;/code&gt; to &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo;. For other models, such as Qwen 3 32B or Qwen 3 30B A3B, we also need to enable the thinking mode, i.e., &lt;code&gt;enable_thinking&lt;/code&gt; parameter to &amp;ldquo;True&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-conversation&#34;&gt;Example Conversation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is an example conversation using the above prompt, using Grok 4 (in the API, it is &lt;code&gt;grok-4-0709&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User:&lt;/strong&gt; Can you independently discover Nash equilibrium (Nash, econometrica 1950) if I just provide you with three ingredients? 1. Cournot competition/equilibrium (1838), 2. Von Neumann and Morgenstern utility, 3. Brouwer or Kakutani Fixed Point Theorems? If so, how and why? if not, why not? step by step. provide tangible example and explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Thought 1: Define the problem clearly.

The core problem is: Given only three specific &amp;#34;ingredients&amp;#34; from economic and mathematical theory—Cournot competition/equilibrium (from Antoine Augustin Cournot&amp;#39;s 1838 work on oligopoly), Von Neumann and Morgenstern&amp;#39;s utility theory (from their 1944 book on game theory and expected utility), and fixed-point theorems (Brouwer&amp;#39;s 1911 theorem or Kakutani&amp;#39;s 1941 generalization)—can I, as an AI reasoning from first principles, independently &amp;#34;discover&amp;#34; (i.e., derive or reconstruct) the concept of Nash equilibrium as presented in John Nash&amp;#39;s 1950 Econometrica paper? If yes, explain how and why step by step with a tangible example. If no, explain why not.

This is not about historical rediscovery but about whether these ingredients logically suffice to derive Nash&amp;#39;s insight without external knowledge of Nash&amp;#39;s work. I must simulate independent reasoning, ensuring it&amp;#39;s sequential, reflective, and from first principles. Key constraints: I cannot use tools like google_search or scrape to look up Nash&amp;#39;s paper or related concepts (that would defeat &amp;#34;independence&amp;#34;); instead, I&amp;#39;ll rely on internalized knowledge and logical deduction.

Break down into atomic sub-tasks:
1. Recall and explain each ingredient in isolation.
2. Identify connections or gaps between them.
3. Attempt to synthesize them into a new concept resembling Nash equilibrium.
4. Provide a tangible example (e.g., a simple game) to illustrate the synthesis.
5. Evaluate if this synthesis truly &amp;#34;discovers&amp;#34; Nash equilibrium, including why it works or fails.
6. Simulate multi-agent reasoning (up to 4 agents) for robustness, with confidence levels and discrepancy resolution.
7. Integrate into a comprehensive answer, iterating if needed (aim for convergence in &amp;lt;=10 steps; terminate early if trivial or convergent).

Quick data completeness check: The query is clear and unambiguous—no missing parameters or edge cases (e.g., it&amp;#39;s not overly minimal input). All ingredients are well-defined historically. Proceed to sub-task 1.

Thought 2: Solve sub-task 1—Recall and explain each ingredient.

- Cournot competition/equilibrium (1838): This is a model of imperfect competition (oligopoly) where a small number of firms produce homogeneous goods and simultaneously choose output quantities to maximize profits, taking rivals&amp;#39; outputs as given. The equilibrium is a set of quantities where each firm&amp;#39;s choice is optimal given others&amp;#39; choices—no firm wants to unilaterally deviate. It&amp;#39;s an early example of strategic interdependence, solved via best-response functions (reaction curves) intersecting.

- Von Neumann and Morgenstern utility (1944): This introduces expected utility theory for rational decision-making under uncertainty. Agents have utility functions over outcomes, and in games, they maximize expected utility. It formalizes zero-sum games and minimax strategies but focuses on cooperative and two-person zero-sum settings. Key: Utilities are cardinal (measurable) and allow for mixed strategies (probabilities over actions).

- Brouwer/Kakutani Fixed Point Theorems: Brouwer&amp;#39;s theorem states that any continuous function from a compact convex set (e.g., a closed ball) to itself has a fixed point (a point x where f(x) = x). Kakutani generalizes this to upper hemicontinuous set-valued functions (correspondences) on compact convex sets, ensuring a fixed point exists. These are topological tools for proving existence in economics/math (e.g., equilibrium in markets).

These are building blocks. No immediate conflicts; they span economics (Cournot), game theory (vNM), and math (fixed points).

Thought 3: Solve sub-task 2—Identify connections or gaps.

Connections:
- Cournot is a specific non-cooperative game (simultaneous quantity-setting) with a solution like a mutual best-response point.
- vNM utility provides a framework for players to have preferences over probabilistic outcomes, enabling mixed strategies.
- Fixed-point theorems can prove existence of points where functions/correspondences map to themselves, which could model &amp;#34;equilibrium&amp;#34; as a fixed point of best-response mappings.

Gaps:
- Cournot is limited to quantity competition in oligopoly; it doesn&amp;#39;t generalize to arbitrary games or n-players with finite strategies.
- vNM focuses on zero-sum/cooperative games; it lacks a general non-cooperative equilibrium concept for multi-player, non-zero-sum settings.
- Fixed points are abstract; applying them requires defining a game&amp;#39;s strategy space as compact/convex and best responses as continuous/set-valued.

To &amp;#34;discover&amp;#34; Nash, I&amp;#39;d need to generalize Cournot&amp;#39;s mutual best-response idea using vNM utilities for any finite game, then use Kakutani to prove existence via fixed points in mixed strategies.

Thought 4: Solve sub-task 3—Attempt synthesis.

Synthesizing step by step from first principles:
1. Start with Cournot as inspiration: In Cournot, equilibrium is where each player&amp;#39;s strategy (quantity) is a best response to others&amp;#39;. This is non-cooperative and stable against unilateral deviation.
2. Generalize using vNM: Extend to any finite game with n players, each with finite pure strategies. Use vNM utility to allow mixed strategies (probability distributions over pure strategies), making strategy spaces convex (simplexes are convex).
3. Define best responses: For each player, the best-response correspondence maps others&amp;#39; strategy profiles to the set of the player&amp;#39;s strategies that maximize their expected utility.
4. Apply fixed point: The overall best-response correspondence (product over players) is set-valued and upper hemicontinuous (under continuity assumptions on utilities). By Kakutani, it has a fixed point—a strategy profile where each player&amp;#39;s strategy is in their best-response set to others. This is exactly a equilibrium where no one deviates unilaterally.

This reconstructs Nash&amp;#39;s insight: A Nash equilibrium is a fixed point of the best-response correspondence in mixed strategies.

Why does this work? These ingredients provide the strategic interdependence (Cournot), utility maximization over probabilities (vNM), and existence proof (Kakutani). Nash himself cited Cournot and vNM, using Kakutani.

Thought 5: Solve sub-task 4—Provide tangible example.

Consider a simple 2-player game like Prisoner&amp;#39;s Dilemma (PD), which fits non-cooperative settings.

- Players: Two prisoners (A, B).
- Strategies: Confess (C) or Deny (D).
- Payoffs (utilities, per vNM): If both Deny, both get -1 (light sentence). If one Confesses and other Denies, Confessor gets 0 (free), Denier gets -10 (heavy). If both Confess, both get -5.

Pure-strategy analysis (inspired by Cournot&amp;#39;s mutual best responses):
- Best response to Deny: Confess (0 &amp;gt; -1).
- Best response to Confess: Confess (-5 &amp;gt; -10).
- Equilibrium: Both Confess (-5 each). No unilateral deviation improves (if A Denies while B Confesses, A gets -10 &amp;lt; -5).

To generalize with mixed strategies (vNM): Let p = prob A Confesses, q = prob B Confesses. Strategy space: [0,1] for each (compact, convex).
- Expected utility for A: U_A(p,q) = p*q*(-5) + p*(1-q)*0 + (1-p)*q*(-10) + (1-p)*(1-q)*(-1).
- Best response for A: Choose p to max U_A given q (similar for B).
- Fixed point: Find (p*, q*) where p* is best vs q*, and vice versa. (In PD, it&amp;#39;s (1,1)—pure strategy.)

Using Kakutani: The best-response map BR: [0,1]^2 -&amp;gt; subsets of [0,1]^2 is upper hemicontinuous, so has fixed point—proving existence.

This &amp;#34;discovers&amp;#34; Nash equilibrium independently for this game.

Thought 6: Solve sub-task 5—Evaluate if this truly discovers Nash.

Yes, it does: The synthesis yields the exact definition (strategy profile where no unilateral deviation improves expected utility) and existence proof for finite games in mixed strategies, matching Nash&amp;#39;s 1950 paper. Why? The ingredients suffice logically—Cournot gives the non-cooperative best-response idea, vNM enables mixed strategies and utilities, Kakutani proves existence without solving explicitly. No major gaps; Nash built directly on these.

If not fully independent (e.g., if my internalized knowledge biases me), the reasoning path is traceable from the ingredients alone.

Thought 7: Solve sub-task 6—Simulate multi-agent reasoning.

Agent 1 (Economist perspective): Synthesis works perfectly—Cournot is proto-Nash for specific games, vNM adds utilities for general prefs, Kakutani seals existence. Confidence: High. Rationale: Historical links are direct; no uncertainties beyond assuming finite games.

Agent 2 (Mathematician perspective): Yes, but requires assuming strategy spaces are compact convex (from mixed strategies via vNM). Kakutani fits better than Brouwer for set-valued BR. Confidence: Medium-high. Rationale: Uncertainty if utilities are continuous (assumed, but not always true in edge cases).

Agent 3 (Game Theorist perspective): Discovers it, as PD example shows. Extends to n-players easily. Confidence: High. Rationale: Matches Nash&amp;#39;s non-cooperative focus, unlike vNM&amp;#39;s zero-sum emphasis.

Agent 4 (Philosopher perspective): Arguably yes, but &amp;#34;discovery&amp;#34; implies novelty; if reasoning is post-hoc, it&amp;#39;s reconstruction. Confidence: Medium. Rationale: Uncertainty in true independence without historical blinders.

Discrepancies: Minor—Agent 4 questions &amp;#34;independence,&amp;#34; Agent 2 notes edge assumptions. Resolution: Majority (3/4) agree on yes; synthesize by noting it&amp;#39;s a valid logical derivation, even if not historically novel. Discrepancies minor; no major conflicts. Terminate iteration early (convergence after 1 round).

Thought 8: Solve sub-task 7—Integrate into comprehensive solution. Early termination: Synthesis converges, query not trivial but resolved without further iteration.

Final Answer: Yes, I can independently discover (i.e., logically derive) the Nash equilibrium concept using these three ingredients. Here&amp;#39;s how and why, step by step, with the tangible example above.

1. **Start with Cournot as the seed**: It provides the idea of a non-cooperative equilibrium based on mutual best responses in a strategic setting.

2. **Incorporate vNM utility**: This allows generalizing to any finite game with mixed strategies, where players maximize expected utility.

3. **Apply fixed-point theorem**: Use Kakutani to prove a fixed point exists in the best-response correspondence, ensuring equilibrium.

Why? These ingredients logically bridge to Nash&amp;#39;s insight without needing more—no external concepts required. If not (counterargument): The jump to general n-player finite games isn&amp;#39;t explicit in Cournot (which is continuous quantities), but vNM&amp;#39;s game framework and fixed points enable it naturally. The PD example shows it tangibly works.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Above example is a naive attempt to derive Nash equilibrium using only three ingredients as a knowledge bundle. One can think of this as a naive, ex-post exercise of whether an AI can creatively think about some abstract concepts with just a bundle of prior knowledge. This is by no means an extensive evaluation of whether AI can produce an entirely new knowledge or invention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I am super happy with this setup. It allows me to initiate conversations with LLMs in a structured way, ensuring that the AI can reason deeply and systematically. The example conversation demonstrates how the AI can apply the prompt effectively to tackle a bit complex question step by step. I have also tried this prompt initation setup to some of my coding exercises (usually in R and sometimes in Python). Toolings (i.e., MCP) such as sequential thinking, web search, file read, fetch, and scrape are incredibly useful for me to get the most out of LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From closed source model, nowadays I mainly use Grok (Grok 4 or Grok 3 mini high) or Gemini (2.5 Pro or flash). For open-source model, via API, I use DeepSeek R1 0528. These models are super cheap in terms of cost (dollar per million tokens), except -of course- Grok 4 and Gemini 2.5 Pro (granted, they are far cheaper than OpenAI o3 or any alternatives from Anthropic). Sometimes, I do not feel satisfied with Grok&amp;rsquo;s answers, then I can ask DeepSeek to re-evaluate Grok&amp;rsquo;s answers. Sometimes, Gemini. Then, I just need to iterate between these models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For local models, I use Qwen 3 32B, Phi 4 Reasoning Plus 14B, or DeepSeek R1 0528 Distilled Qwen 3 8B. Sometimes, I still go back to Qwen 2.5 coder for coding exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My real problem with LLMs so far is the limit in context length, especially for local models! This problem impacts many things such as the ability of a model to digest an entire paper or reading the whole code source, for example. That is from the input side. From the output side, you also have this type of length limit! Some smart people must have been working on this topic to optimize these things. I hope we can get much improvement in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any suggestions or improvements, feel free to share! I am always looking for ways to enhance my interactions with LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan&#39;s Iron Mastery v. Indonesia&#39;s Refining Struggles</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/indonesia_iron_refine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/indonesia_iron_refine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we now understand a fundamental disparity in iron refining between Japan and Indonesia, and it is deeply unsettling, frankly frustrating, how these differences played out despite shared geographical advantages. Let us think from first-principles, I will outline two key bottlenecks that made iron refining far more challenging in Indonesia. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a historical curiosity, it is a lesson in how basic truths about resources, physics, and economics can lead to stark divergences. I will keep this as analytical as possible, grounded in first-principles reasoning and economic theory, while being true to myself in ranting about systemic failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the first bottleneck: the first-principle limit rooted in the physics and chemistry of iron refining. At its core, refining iron involves reducing ore to metal through high-temperature smelting, which demands high energy efficiency and careful impurity management. Both Japan and Indonesia benefit from Ring of Fire geology, providing volcanic iron deposits, but Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s ores were inherently more difficult to process. Historical and geological sources indicate that deposits like those in the Barito region were frequently contaminated with impurities such as sulfur, aluminum oxides, silicates, and nickel, which is prevalent in Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s laterite soils. This mix of elements lowers iron yield by complicating the smelting process, as nickel requires additional separation techniques and increases fuel consumption for purification, making the entire operation less efficient. In contrast, Indonesian smelting methods were typically bloomery-like and low-temperature, relying on simple furnaces that couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle impurities well, yielding inconsistent results compared to Japan&amp;rsquo;s advanced Tatara furnace system. It&amp;rsquo;s not just misfortune, it is a fundamental physical constraint where the chemistry of impure ores demands greater precision and resources, often resulting in suboptimal metal quality. Tropical weathering worsened this, degrading ore through rain and erosion, while Japan&amp;rsquo;s more uniform iron sand allowed for better control and outcomes. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t preordained—Japan was backed into innovation by necessity, driven by their institutional environment of isolation and conflict, while Indonesia was lulled into complacency by abundant trade access, highlighting a systemic inability to overcome basic resource limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second bottleneck is the economic disincentives that hampered progress, a direct outcome of how demand and opportunity costs shaped priorities. From an economic perspective, refining iron relies on incentives tied to production costs, market demand, and trade-offs, with demand being a critical driver. Both Japan and Indonesia experienced periods of internal conflict and &amp;ldquo;warring states,&amp;rdquo; but the effects diverged significantly. In Japan, constant warfare among feudal lords created a high-stakes demand for durable, high-quality swords and weapons, directly boosting the need for efficient iron refining and spurring technological improvements. This demand-side pressure, turned refining into a strategic necessity, fostering innovation and scale. In contrast, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s society, governed by warlords and fragmented powers, did not generate the same demand, as weapons like the keris were viewed more as mythical, symbolic tools rather than practical instruments of war. This functional distinction meant that iron refining lacked the economic pull to evolve, remaining marginal and underdeveloped. Adding to this, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s control of trade chokepoints like the Malacca Strait provided easy access to imported iron products from regions like India and China, making domestic refining less competitive and further diverting resources toward trade. Economic theory underscores this imbalance: opportunity costs favored imports over investment in local capabilities, perpetuating dependency, while Japan&amp;rsquo;s isolation eliminated such options, forcing self-reliant creativity. It&amp;rsquo;s a stark example of how economic logic can entrench disparities, with short-term trade benefits overshadowing long-term development potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s the kicker: finding solutions to this mess is extremely challenging without confronting human capital and government overreach. Human capital could be transformative, involving investments in education and skills to develop a workforce capable of tackling technological barriers and enabling more efficient refining through contemporary methods. Yet, this approach stumbles without aligned economic incentives, as skilled workers would migrate to more profitable sectors or regions. Then there&amp;rsquo;s the government aspect, where excessive interventions—such as overly restrictive regulations or misguided subsidies—distort markets and undermine the incentives essential for innovation. In Indonesia, historical and ongoing issues with bureaucratic inefficiency and corruption have exacerbated these problems, making self-sustained progress feel unattainable. We&amp;rsquo;d need a significant shift toward reduced interference to allow market forces and human ingenuity to operate freely, but with entrenched institutional flaws, it remains a formidable obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPDP and STEM</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/lpdp_rant_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent decision by LPDP to increase the share of STEM scholarship recipients is a much-needed correction. For too long, Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s scholarship allocation has favored ambiguous “development” fields or MBA tracks that yield little marginal societal benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the caveat is concerning: this new prioritization is tethered to vaguely defined “strategic industries.” That is a flawed approach. Today’s strategic darling might be AI and semiconductors; tomorrow, it could be humanoid robots, neuromorphic computing, or quantum photonics. Technological breakthroughs are inherently uncertain. Anchoring public investment to a narrow and bureaucratically defined industry list risks missing the real innovation curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Indonesia truly needs is a coherent, bottom-up construction of the technological stack, starting from fundamentals. This means serious investment in mathematics, computer science, electrical engineering (beyond just power systems and power management, ok?), and certainly physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in AI, Indonesia lags not just because of a lack of “AI specialists,” but also due to weak foundations across the tech stack. Without that, no amount of AI hype will yield genuine capability. For example, I’ve tried to find people in Indonesia working on modern reinforcement learning methods (like GRPO), and it’s nearly impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A broader philosophical correction is also in order: stop treating the government as a job provider. That logic has led to bloated bureaucracy, misaligned incentives, and widespread rent-seeking. The government’s role is not to create jobs directly, but to fix market failures, provide public goods, and de-risk fundamental investments, like basic research and core human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still hold the view that the net benefit of LPDP is close to zero. But if LPDP must exist, its limited resources should be directed to high-benefit, high-demand sectors: public health (doctors, nurses, psychologists) and education (especially STEM teachers for K-12). There is little justification for subsidizing MBAs or vaguely defined “development” degrees abroad; these carry ambiguous returns and often serve only to reinforce domestic elitism rather than genuinely improve the nation’s human capital.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Education Collapse</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/post_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we have two main problems in the Indonesian education system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every kid progresses to the next grade automatically and unconditionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The normalization of the belief that ‘good schools and university education are a right for everyone’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem concerns the destruction of the core incentives of studying, especially in the Indonesian setting. Why would Indonesian kids put effort, do homework, and actually learn something in school, if they will automatically pass and go to the next grade. Zero incentives. None. I’ve seen with my own eyes that some of my family members possess disturbingly subpar abilities in math, reasoning, and reading. This is irreparable damage done by the people at the top, and those people never apologize. A betrayal of duty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same mechanics also apply to the teachers. You would probably have seen that the teaching quality is decreasing. And if I were a teacher, watching students breeze through the system no matter what, I’d ask myself: why am I here, hello? Teachers would not have appropriate incentives to improve their skills. So, you have this rapid depreciation and deterioration of human capital among teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is a typical concern raised and, frankly, promoted by faculty and activists, often educated in Western institutions and steeped in left-leaning idealism. But, it feels good! Yes, we can feel good about it. Sure. But reality slaps us. Schools and universities have minimum budgets that rely mostly on government funding. Government budgets are scarce and stagnant in real terms, so schools must chase funding however they can. You and I both agree that the Indonesian government is just a collection of bandits, pirates, and warlords; they wouldn’t care about the social welfare or any of these craps. Do not easily blame schools or universities that try to raise funding by other means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this policy madness stems from trying to universalize a moral ideal without regard for local realities. Think of the zoning school system. Look closely, compare it to a decade ago, and tell me you don’t see the death of public schools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excess Suply of Indonesian Garrulous Class</title>
      <link>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/garrulous_class_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://regikusumaatmadja.com/post/garrulous_class_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t often keep up with events in Indonesia, but lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed the emergence of a new societal group; let&amp;rsquo;s call it the &amp;ldquo;Garrulous Class.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class is characterized by individuals who tend to focus on trivial matters, often discussing &amp;lsquo;big picture&amp;rsquo; topics such as sustainability, youth politics, demographic bonuses, development, inequality, social justice, and more. They often express their views but, in my opinion, lack the ability to provide innovative and significant solutions to the problems they address, despite their fervent attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class is typically found on social media, in universities, within the government, and also among certain segments of private and state-owned enterprises. They are often graduates of Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s top three universities, who then pursue their postgraduate studies in foreign countries, their studies financed by the unwitting Indonesian taxpayers through &amp;lsquo;prestigious&amp;rsquo; government scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first encounter with individuals from this class dates back to my high school and undergraduate years, about a decade ago. There were senior students who attempted to convince us, the freshmen, that &amp;ldquo;we are the future leaders of Indonesia,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;we should consider policies that influence the direction of Indonesia,&amp;rdquo; among other statements. Another interesting instance involves certain companies that employ a large group of policy professionals whose primary role is to communicate with the government and shape policies. Why not simply focus on profitability without relying on government subsidies? This remains a puzzle. To be clear, I once embraced these perspectives and was actually part of this class. Talk about irony!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe that the reason this class is so talkative (hence the name &amp;ldquo;Garrulous Class&amp;rdquo;) is a sense of inadequacy stemming from their lack of technical skills to directly address and solve the issues they raise. The highly educated individuals in this class recognize that they may be overeducated in somewhat impractical fields, lacking necessary technical competencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My concern is that this class will continue to grow while technical experts – those pushing the boundaries of knowledge, economy, and society – are leaving for other countries. Consider the number of Indonesian STEM graduates becoming Singaporean citizens, or the number of Indonesian physicists and material scientists who manage to secure funding from the Korean Department of Defense, among other similar cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I have a solution to this perceived oversupply? No, I don&amp;rsquo;t. But I do acknowledge my own bias and disdain for this class. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that I am mistaken. People from this class do find employment, so technically there&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;rsquo;excess supply.&amp;rsquo; Nevertheless, I do hope that society and its decision-makers will come to agree with my viewpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
